Guide to the Frederick Emmons Terman Papers SC0160
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Stanford School of Engineering, 1925-1946; Series II
  - STUDENT-FACULTY RESEARCH., 1928-1935
    - Circuit Design to Improve the-Frequency Response of Output Transformers. Research notes for thesis by Charles Moreno. 1940. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Research by Frederick Terman. 1937-47. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Circuit Design to Improve the Frequency Response of Output Transformers. Charles Moreno. 1940. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - ITT INVENTION DISCLOSURES
    - ITT - Electronics Laboratory Correspondence. 1938-39. (Box 10, Folder I)
    - ITT - Electronics Laboratory Correspondence. 1940-42. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Federal Telecommunications Laboratory (ITT affiliate). 1943 - 49. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - #1 - Loss Modulators (accepted). 1936 - 39. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - #2 - Linear Amplifying System (filed). 1939 - 40. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - #3 - Modulation Systems (filed). 1938 - 39. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - #4 - Multirange Meters (declined). 1939. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - #5 - Stabilized Oscillation Generator (accepted). 1939 - 41. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - #6-7 - Modulation Systems (accepted). 1939 - 40. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - #8 - Distortion Correction Remodulation System (declined). 1939. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - #9 - Distortion Correction (declined) [n.d.] (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - #10 - Frequency Changing System (declined). 1939 - 40. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - #11 - Distortion Correction (declined). [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - #12 - Distortion Correction (declined). 1939. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - #13 - Distortion Correction (declined). [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - #14 - Multiple Lead Tube (declined). 1939 - 40. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - #15 - Sound Absorbing System (accepted). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - #16 - Direction Finding System (accepted). 1939 - 40. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - #17 - Stabilized Amplifier (declined). 1938 - 40. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - #18 - Diode-Type Detector for Heterodyne Signals (declined). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - #19 - Method of Removing Amplitude Modulation (accepted). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - #20 - Improvement in Klystron Detector (accepted). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - #21 - Method of Controlling High-Frequency Characteristics (declined). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - #22 - Method of Reducing Low Frequency Regeneration (accepted). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - #23 - Coupling Systems for Power Amplifiers (accepted). 1940 - 42. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - #24 - High Efficiency Loss Modulator (accepted). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - #25 - Simple Impedance Inverter (declined). 1940. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - #26 - High Efficiency Amplifier (accepted). 1940-41. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - #27 - Diversity Receiving Systems (accepted). 1941. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - #28 - A System of High Level Frequency Modulation (accepted). 1942. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - #27a - Diversity Systems employing combined Amplitude and Frequency Modulation (declined) [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - #29 - obtaining Correct Radio Compass Bearings (declined). 1942. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - #30 - Method of Avoiding Hunting in Control Systems (declined). [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - [unnumbered] - High-Density Beam (accepted). [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Group II - Agreements and General Correspondence. 1936 - 40. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Group II - #1 - Modulator (declined). 1936 - 37. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Group II - #2 - Stabilized Amplifier (filed). 1937 - 41. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Group II - #3 - Linear Amplifying System (filed). 1939 - 41. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Group II - #4 - Improvement in Grid-Modulated Amplifier (filed, but dropped). 1939 - 40. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Group II - #5-9 - Distortion Correction System (declined). 1939 - 40. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Group II - #10 - Direction Finding System (declined). 1939. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Group II - #11 - Multiple Lead Tubes (declined). 1939 - 40. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Group II - #12 - Sound Absorbing System (declined). 1940 - 41. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Group II - #13 - Diode Type Detector for Heterodyne Signals (declined). 1940. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Group II - #14 - Method of Removing Amplitude Modulation. 1940. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Group II - #15-17 - Miscellaneous (declined). 1940 - 41. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - STANFORD ELECTRONICS LABORATORY CORRESPONDENCE FILES., 1951-1954
    - Administration. 1951-55. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Air Force - general correspondence. 1951 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Airborne Instrument Laboratory. 1951 - 52. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Applied Engineering Laboratory: Moving. 1953 54. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Atomic Energy Commission. 1955. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ayer, W. E. July 1955. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - B. 1952-54. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Bacon, David C. 1954-56. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Budget. 1952. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Budget. 1953 - 54. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Budget. 1954 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Building. 1951 - 53. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Burroughs Corporation. 1954. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Buss, Robert. 1952-54. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Cate, Donald. 1955. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Classifications. 1954 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Classified Materials, Receipts for. 1954 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Contract Negotiations - general. 1950 - 54. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Contractor's Meeting. August 1955. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Contracts: Air Force - Miscellaneous. 1953 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Contracts: Air Force - AF 19(604)-686. 1952 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Contracts: Air Force - AF 19(604)-795. 1953 - 56. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Contracts: Air Force - AF 19(604)-1031. 1954 - 56. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Contracts: Air Force - AF 19(604)-1065. 1954 - 55. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Contracts: Air Force - AF 30(602)-8. Final Report: Low Frequency Navigation and Guidance Systems. 1953. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Contracts: Air Force - AF 33(600)-27784. 1954 - 56. (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Contracts: Air Force - Single Side Band. 1954. (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Contracts: Air Force -Whistlers. 1955 - 56. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Contracts: Air Force -Purchase Request 559169. 1956. (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Contracts: Air Force -Purchase Request 646609. 1956. (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Contracts: Army Signal Corps. 1953 - 56. (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Contracts: Atomic Energy Commission. 1956. (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Contracts: General Electric. 1954 - 55. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Contracts: Hewlett-Packard. 1953 - 55. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Contracts: Lincoln Project. 1954. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Contracts: Litton Industries. 1955. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Contracts: Miscellaneous. 1953 - 54. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Contracts: National Bureau of Standards - CST-3071. 1955. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Contracts: National Bureau of Standards - CST-10751. 1947 - 55. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Contracts: National Science Foundation - Grant NSF/IGY. 1955. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - general. 1952 5 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr - 225(04). 1951-53. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr 225(04). Status Reports. 1952 - 53. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr 225(05). 1952 - 53. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr 225(07). 1951 - 53. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr 225(10). 1951 - 53. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr 225(10), Project 330. 1952 - 53. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr 225(12). 1952 - 55. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr - 251(07). 1951 - 56. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Contracts: Office of Naval Research - Nonr - 251(32). 1950-55. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Contracts: Penta Laboratories. 1953 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Contracts: Sandia Corporation. 1955. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Contracts: University of California. 1954. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Contracts: University of Colorado. 1952 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Contracts: Varian Associates. 1951 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Contracts: Villard. 1953 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Dunn, Donald A. 1953 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - E. 1952 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Edson, William A. 1952 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Eitel-McCullough Grant. 1952 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Electron Tube Conference. 1952 - 53; 1955. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Field, Lester M. 1951 - 53. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Fire Protection Reinspection Report. 1954. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - G. 1952 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Ginzton, Edward L. 1951 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Gilfillan Brothers. 1948; 1953. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - H. 1952 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Hallicrafters. 1954. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Hare, Milton. 1955. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Harris, Donald B. 1951-55. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Hewlett-Packard. 1952-54. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Holt, Roland. 1952 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Huggins Laboratories. 1955. (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - I. 1953 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Instrument Committee Minutes. 1954. (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - J. 1952 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Kaisel, Sidney F. 1952 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Kohl, Walter H. 1954 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - L. 1953 - 54. (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Liaison Information. 1951 - 52. (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Lincoln Project. 1951 - 53. (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Linvill, John. 1955. (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - M. 1951 - 55. (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - McGhie, L. Farrell. 1952 53. (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Matthews, Allen R. 1951 53. (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Medical Electronics. 1955. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Michigan, University of. 1951 - 55. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Microwave - general. 1953 - 54. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Projects: Lists of Reports. 1955. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Models. 1951 - 54. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - N. 1953 - 54. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Office of Naval Research: general correspondence. 1951 - 55. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Operational Reports. 1951 - 1952. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Organizational Charts. 1952 - 53. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - P. 1952 - 55. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Patents. 1951 - 56. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Personnel Assignments. 1953. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Personnel Directories. 1952 - 53. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Personnel Prospects: Inactive. 1950 - 53. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Pettit, Joseph M. 1951 - 54. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Proposals for Applied Research and Development. 1951 - 52. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Publications. 1951 - 55. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - R. 1952 - 53. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Rambo, William. 1951 - 56. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Rambo, William. Project S-440. 1954-55. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Rand Corporation. 1951. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Rapid Scan Receivers. 1951 - 54. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Raytheon. 1954 - 55. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Research Corporation. 1953. (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - S. 1951 - 56. (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Safety Committee Minutes. 1953 - 56. (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Salaries. 1953 - 56. (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Security. 1952 - 56. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Senior Staff. 1951 - 54. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Signal Corps - general correspondence. 1952 54. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Spangenberg, Karl. 1951 - 56. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Electronics Laboratories: Organization. 1955. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Electronics Newsletter. 1952. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Stanford Laboratories, Inc. 1955. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Stanford University. 1951 - 52. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Susskind, Charles. 1953 - 55. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Sylvania Electric Products. 1952 - 54. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Sylvania - Electronic Defense Laboratory. 1953 - 54. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - T. 1955. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Meetings. 1951. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Meetings. 1952. (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Meetings. 1953. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Meetings. 1954. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Meetings. 1955. (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Technical Advisory Committee Meeting. Spring, 1956. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Technical Program. 1950 - 55. (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Technical Program Committee. 1954 - 55. (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Television. March 1955. (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Terman, Frederick E.: memos to files. 1950 - 53. (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Terman, Frederick E.: Personal correspondence. 1954 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Tube Shop. 1952. (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - V. 1952 - 55. (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - W. 1953 - 56. (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Waterman, Alan. 1953 54. (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Watkins, Dean H. 1953 56. (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Z. 1952 - 55. (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - MICROWAVE LABORATORY
    - Microwave Laboratory - general correspondence. 1950 - 52. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Microwave Laboratory - general correspondence. 1954 - 56. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Budgets and Finance. 1951 - 54. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Building. 1952. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Contracts: Ferroelectricity Project. 1951 - 54. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Contracts: General Electric Company. 1952 - 55. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Contracts: Miscellaneous. 1954 - 55. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - General Electric Company - general. 1951 - 55. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Linear Accelerator Accounts. 1949 - 54. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Microwave Laboratory Medical Program. 1952 - 54. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Motz, Hans. 1951 - 52. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Pierce, J. R. November 1951. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - TEACHING MATERIALS
    - Network Theorems: Syllabus [n.d.] (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Networks: Lecture Notes [n.d.] (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Power Lines: Data and Notes [n.d.] (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Transmission Circuits: Syllabus [n.d.] (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Course Evaluation: Electrical Engineering 110. Winter Quarter 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Course Evaluation: Electrical Engineering 110 [n.d.] (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Course Evaluation: Electrical Engineering 111 [n.d.] (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Course Evaluation: Electrical Engineering 112. Spring Quarter 1952. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Course Evaluation: Electrical Engineering 11' Spring Quarter 1953. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Course Evaluation: Electrical Engineering 161. Winter Quarter 1955. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Course Evaluation: Winter Quarter 1954. Class not identified. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Electrical Engineering 160, Fall 1953;1954. (Box 20, Folder I)
    - Electrical Engineering 162, Spring 1954;1955. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Electrical Engineering 161, Winter 1953/54; 1954/55. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Electrical Engineering 110, 111,112; 1947,1948,1950. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Electrical Engineering course work, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Radio Engineering: Misc. classes, 1937-41. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Transmission Circuits, 1939. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Transmission Circuits, exams, 1933-1940. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Transmission Circuits, exams cont., 1933-1940. (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Stanford Administration, 1948-1972; Series III
  Boxes 1-60: Provosts' Personal Papers, 1955-65. These files consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports and clipping covering all phases of Dr. Terman's activities as Provost. They were called "personal" by Dr. Terman's office because they were controlled by Terman's own secretary, rather than being a part of the central President's and Provost's record group. The contents, however, deal strictly with University-related matters. These records provide revealing insights into Dr. Terman's philosophy and methods of strengthening academic departments as well as the general functioning of the highest levels of university administration. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder.
  Boxes 61-63: Provost's staff meeting, 1959-65. Agenda, minutes, and supporting documents for the biweekly meetings of Dr. Terman's office staff.
  Boxes 64-67: Studies for the President, 1966-75 Following Dr. Terman's retirement as Provost in 1965, he continued work part-time as a consultant to the President of the University. In this capacity, he carried out several studies for President Sterling and his successors, including control of faculty size, fringe benefits, retirement pensions, and funding of Stanford's professional schools. These four boxes contain correspondence, data, working papers and reports related to these studies.
  Boxes 68-75: Data processing in the Provost's Office, 1955-75. When the Registrar's Office computerized its operations in 1955, Dr. Terman saw the opportunity to obtain a vast amount of statistical data on the educational activities within Stanford. With a grant from the Ford Foundation, Terman and Professor Robert Oakford were able to program the system to provide a variety of information in a form that was useful to the Provost. These boxes contain computer print-outs divided into volumes by topics, which include statistics on courses taught by each instructor, enrollment statistics, age and salary distribution among faculty.
  Boxes 76-77: Budget working papers, 1955-65. Binders containing memoranda, data, and calculations compiled by Terman to be used in figuring yearly budgets. Arranged chronologically.
  Box 78: Miscellaneous administrative files, 1948-65.. Folders 1 -7 contain files on graduate division accounts; and Terman's study of undergraduate education. Folders 8 -13 are concerned with the search for the successor for Stanford's deceased President Donald B. Tresidder. Terman was elected to the Faculty Advisory Committee which recommended presidential candidates to the Board of Trustees. These files contain correspondence, minutes, agenda, and lists of candidates relevant to this task.
  - PROVOST'S PERSONAL PAPERS
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Admissions Committee. 1956-57. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Admission Committee. 1958. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Admissions Committee. 1959. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Admissions Committee. 1960 - 61. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Admissions Committee. 1962 - 63. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Admissions Committee. 1964 - 68 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Admissions - Transfer Program. 1958 - 60. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Administrative Policies. 1955; 1958 - 62. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Policies. 1963 - 67. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Policies. 1968 - 70. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Research Projects Agency (ARPA). 1961 64. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Advisory Board. 1956 - 62. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Advisory Board. 1963 - 65. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Advisory Board - Forms Revision. 1963 - 65. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Aeronautical Engineering. 1958 - 63. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Aeronautical Engineering. 1964 - 70. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Agency for International Development (AID). 1962, 1964. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Air Force. 1960 - 65. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Algard, F. Thomas. 1961 64. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - American Association of University Professors. 1959 - 67. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ampex. 1960 - 64. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Anthropology. 1957 - 65. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Applied Mathematics. 1966. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Applied Physics. 1961 - 65. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Art Gallery and Museum - Art Department. 1956 - 61. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Art Gallery and Museum - Art Department. 1963 - 64. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Asian Languages. 1956 - 63. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Athletics. 1957 - 61. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Axt, Richard. 1960 - 64. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - B-BO (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - BR-BZ (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Barclay, Tom. 1964. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Behavioral Sciences. 1954 - 61. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Berelson Graduate Study. 1958. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Biochemistry. 1956 - 59. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Biological Sciences. 1955 - 59. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Biology. 1960. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Biology. 1961 - 62. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Biology. 1963 - 65. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Biology - Department Head; Department Reappraisal 1963 - 65. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Biology Search Committee. 1965. (Box 5, Folder I)
    - Biology: Vanderbilt Foundation. 1960. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Biomedical Engineering. 1960-67. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Biophysics, general. 1959 - 65. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Biophysics, Review of. 1961. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Biophysics, Review of. 1962. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Biophysics, Review of. 1963. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Biophysics, Review of -Ginzton. 1960 - 63. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bowker, Albert. 1957 - 64. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Bowker, Albert. 1965 - 71. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Bowker successor. 1963. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Braun Trust. 1960. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Brooks, Howard. 1957 - 66. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bunzel, John. 1957 - 63. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Business, Graduate School of. 1955 - 58. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Business, Graduate School of. 1959. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Business, Graduate School of. 1960 - 73. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Business, Graduate School of Long-range plans. 1956 - 64. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Business Office. 1959 - 65. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - C-CL (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - CO-CZ (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - California Institute of Technology. 1956 - 63. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - California, U. of - Relations. 1958 - 62. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - California, U. of - Relations. 1963. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - California, U. of - Relations. 1964. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - California, U. of - Relations. 1965. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Carnegie Institution. 1962 - 65. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Case System. 1966. Center for Materials Research (CMR) See Materials Research Center (b. 38, f. 7). (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Chemical Engineering. 1949 - 55. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chemical Engineering. 1955 - 64. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry. 1949; 1954 - 60. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Chemistry. 1960 - 65. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chemistry - Biochemistry. 1958 - 59. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Chemistry Building. 1959 - 60. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Chemistry Building. 1959. USPHS Grants. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Chemistry Building. 1960 - 61. Stauffer Dedication. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Chemistry Building and Program. 1962 - 64. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Chemistry - Classified Contracts (Aerosol Lab). 1951 -60. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Chemistry - Djerassi. 1959 - 61. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry - Finances. 1959 - 61. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Chemistry Headship Search - general. 1956 - 59. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Chemistry Headship Search - names of potential candidates. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Chemistry Headship Search - Dossiers on 3 top candidates (all of whom declined position). (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Chemistry Headship - Johnson. 1958 - 59. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Chemistry - Johnson. 1959 - 60. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Chemistry - Microanalytical. 1960 - 61. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Chemistry - New faculty. 1959 - 62. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Chemistry Promotion - inactive. 1959 - 61. (Box 10, Folder I)
    - Chemistry Promotion - PACE. 1959 - 61. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry - Useful data. 1949 - 59. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Chemistry - Weissman. 1959. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Civil Engineering. 1958 - 63. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Civil Engineering. 1963 - 65. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Classics. 1962; 1965. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Classified Research. 1966 - 70. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Coe, William Robertson - Fund for American Studies. 1956 - 64. (Box 11, Folder 1)